Guide to the Sam Shepard and Johnny Dark Collection
The Wittliff Collections
- Audio Material, 1976-2002, undated
  - Tape 009 Side A: "Sam and John reminiscing 4/12/94" Side B: unlabeled, April 12, 1994 (Box 7)
    Side B: A continuation of the conversation from Side A. Johnny talks about past relationships, breaking into one of his ex girlfriends apartments and getting arrested, and having remorse about messing up his last serious relationships. After his conversation is over with Sam, the recording switches to a conversation between Johnny and Scarlett on various subjects. They talk about the question of what it is to be an adult and talk it out between each other.
  - Tape 010 Side A: "Iowa" Side B: Sam and Darl O-Lan Scarlett" [Note: no summary available] (Box 7)
  - Tape 011 Side A: "Phone 2002 Sam-Gene-Geenie" Side B: unlabeled (Box 7)
    Side A: Johnny has a conversation about a live show that is friend on the other end of the line played. Johnny also talks about a book that he is writing and how he wrote the ending first and is writing backwards. Later on, Johnny talks to Sam about the various guns they own.
    Side B: Johnny talks with an unknown woman about writing his biography and the various things he has done with it, such as writing his own death at the end. The woman also talks to Johnny about writing her biography as well. The conversation eventually turns to talk about how Johnny went around and interviewed the people that he knows for his biography so that they could write their own story for it. Johnny tells a story of a former girlfriend who was forced by her father to drop out of college and forbade her from seeing him again and how they finally met up 30 years later.
  - Tape 012 Side A: "Sam 92" Side B: unlabeled (Box 7)
    Side A: During this conversation, Sam tells Johnny about reading Great River and how the writer, Paul Horgan, has a way with writing. They also discuss continuity in life and with people and relationships. Sam talks with Johnny about moving himself to Texas. (Sound missing due to technical difficulties during digital transfer, beginning at 21:27 and ends at 22:00)
    Side B: Classical Music recorded by Johnny.
  - Tape 013 Side A: "8/22/95 Sam and John" Side B: unlabeled, August 22, 1995 (Box 7)
    Side A: Johnny talks to Sam about finally understanding Sam's love of driving. Sam tells Johnny a story about a guy he knew who taught his kid how to shoot a .22 by having the kid shoot a cigarette out of his mouth. They also talk about Charles Manson and his magnetism with women, Wang Poe and Buddhism, mind substance and Robin Williams. After the conversation with Sam, the recording picks up mid conversation between Johnny and an unknown woman.
    Side B: Sam talks to Johnny about being flexible and being able to move and relocate. Sam also talks about trying to sell a horse that had bad tendons and using magnets for inflammation. During a second discussion, Sam and Johnny talk about a mutual acquaintance's trip to Spain to meet up with her ex-husband and the author Juan Rulfo.
  - Tape 014 Side A: "10/2001 Sam and John (Typed)" Side B: unlabeled, October 2001 (Box 7)
    Side A: Sam and Johnny talk about a New York Times article about Afghanistan and the Taliban. They also talk about the story of Mohammad and Islam. During their conversation, Sam tells Johnny of the Bohemian Sausage Festival and Johnny reminisces about going to a gun show after meeting up with Sam in Iowa. They also talk about the reactions of people after September 11, 2001 and what to expect in the coming days and the crusades during the middle ages. Sam also talks about writing about his father throughout his life.
    Side B: This side contains music.
  - Tape 015 Side A: "Sam and John 1/3/93" Side B: "Johnny '93", January 3, 1993 (Box 7)
    Side A: Johnny tells Sam a story about working outside, playing racquetball and feeling alone at the Y. Johnny elaborates on loneliness and how people surround themselves with people to not be alone. Their conversation then moves to the Bible and matters that are of a spiritual nature.
    Side B: Johnny talks about feeling like a "sleazy lecher" while telling a story about his last date with a girl and how inappropriate it was. The conversations then changes to the topic of first dates and what to do on them. Johnny reads passages from the book he was writing at the time
  - Tape 016 "Side A 8/28/94 Me and Sam (Both Sides)" (Box 7)
    Side A: The first parts of this recording are voice messages left for Johnny. After the messages, Sam tells a story about his son meeting a girl that he was fixated on at a restaurant. Sam talks about his family, burying his mom and growing up. Johnny talks about having reoccurring dreams about certain people in his life.
    Side B: This is a continuation of side A. They talk about memories and the difference between American and British actors.
  - Tape 017 Side A: "Sam 3/15/95" Side B: "RAMDAS", March 15, 1995 (Box 7)
    Side A: Audio quality is poor due to the quality of the tape it was recorded on. It is hard to hear what is being discussed during parts of the recording.
    Side B: The audio quality is poor due to the quality of the tape. Sound fluctuates between soft and loud. It is difficult to understand what is being discussed.
  - Tape 018 Side A: "Huck Finn Ed Begley" Side B: "Jesse-Sam-John-'79 Aug Jessie Tells Stories (Rasberries)", 1979 (Box 7)
    Side A: This side contains an audiobook excerpt of Huckleberry Finn.
    Side B: Sam's young son Jesse talks about a teacher he doesn't like and tells Sam and Johnny a story entitled "Raspberries".
  - Tape 019 Side A: "Love Mary 87" Side B: "John and Sam Phone Aug 91", August 1991 (Box 7)
    Side A: Johnny discusses various points in his life when he felt he didn't realize his potential, Mary talks about family troubles and turning 50, they talk about Sam and his relationship troubles. Johnny and Mary eventually move on to talk about love. The recording switches to a conversation about Johnny and an unknown woman. The recording switches again to part of a conversation between Sam and Johnny.
    Side B: This recording starts with Johnny having a conversation with an unknown woman, discussing the filming of a movie, taking a trip to Texas, anxiety, and relationship problems.
  - Tape 020 Side A: "Sam and Me 5/10/95 Phone" Side B: unlabeled, May 10, 1995 (Box 7)
    Side A: Johnny and Sam talk about Sam's book that he is finishing, going to the Kentucky Derby and getting an autograph from Eddie Arcaro. The conversation shifts to a discussion about the book Johnny is working on, watching the Pelican Brief with Scarlett and Sam's acting in it. Johnny talks about troubles with drugs, a visit from an old friend, and Sam reads a passage of his book.
    Side B: This side is a continuation of the discussion on the previous side. Johnny candidly talks with an unknown man about beds. The unknown man tells a story about working at a feed and pet store. Johnny talks about certain aspects of the way he was raised, what he likes about the character of Scrooge in A Christmas Carol and why it is the book of choice amongst drug users. Johnny also talks about advice his mother gave him when he was younger.
  - Tape 021 Side A: Best of the Ranch 1976, 1977 Mill Valley Calif" Side B: blank [Note: no summary available] (Box 7)
  - Tape 022 Side A: "SJ 1, Sam and John Sept 82" Side B: "SJ2" [Note: no summary available], September 1982 (Box 7)
  - Tape 023 Side A: Sam 3/28/94, Mother's death, meditation, Mr. Tilly Side B: blank [Note: no summary available], March 28, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Tape 024 Side A: "scarlett's Stories" Side B: "John and Sam, SJ4" [Note: no summary available] (Box 7)
  - Tape 025 Side A: "Feb 1984 New Mexico Sam and Johnny" Side B: unlabeled [Note: no summary available], February 1984 (Box 7)
  - Tape 026 Side A: "Sam 11/22/94" Side B: unlabeled [Note: no summary available], November 22, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Tape 027 Side A: unlabeled Side B: "Sam 1, 1983" [Note: no summary available] (Box 7)
  - Tape 028 Unlabeled (Box 7)
    Side A: This audiotape contains a conversation with Johnny, Sam and a friend about various and random topic such as their views on college and joining the military. They eventually bring out a guitar and write a song about an "avant-garde wacko."
    Side B: This recording begins with Johnny, Sam and an unknown friend playing music on a piano, guitar and harmonica
- Video Material
  Series V: Video Material consists of two items. The first is a VHS tape of home movies shot by Dark. The video quality is relatively poor, but the tape has been digitized and a viewing copy is available. The second item is a DVD of the documentary, Shepard and Dark, directed by Treva Wurmfeld. Access to this DVD is by special permission only.
  - VHS Cassette, "Home Movies 1975 Onward" [DVD copy available] (Box 7)
  - DVD & Blu-ray, Shepard and Dark documentary, 2012 (Box 7)